回顾一下，我们有一个摄像头，它正在观察三维空间中的物体。我们可以
Just to recap we have a camera, which is observing an object in three-dimensional space. We can
将3D空间中对象的位置投影到具有坐标的图像平面中
project the position of the object in 3D space into the image plane where it has a coordinate
U，V。假设相机能够移动并且具有平移速度和旋转
U, V. Assume that the camera is able to move and it has translational velocity and rotational
速度。图像平面上的点的速度与相机空间有关
velocity. The velocity of the point on the image plane is related to the camera spatial
速度由图像雅可比。
velocity by the image Jacobian.
我们可以非常简单地证明这一原则。如果我把头移到右边那么机器人
We can demonstrate this principle very simply. If I move my head to the right then the robot
世界上的其他一切似乎都向左移动了。相反，我转动我的头
and everything else in the world appears to move to the left. If instead I rotate my head
在右边，那么世界上的一切也往往向左移动。
towards the right then everything in the world also tends to move to the left.
移动我的脑袋之间有一种模棱两可的态度;纯粹的翻译到右边和
So there's an ambiguity between moving my head; pure translation to the right and the
把头转到右边。视觉外观有点类似。
rotation of my head to the right. The visual appearance is somewhat similar.
我们需要注意两个重要的概念。第一个问题是明显的。
There are two important concepts that we need to be aware of. The first issue is perceptibly.
通常，当相机移动时，图像平面上的点也会移动。
In general as the camera moves, points on the image plane move as well.
因此在某些情况下，相机会在图像平面中移动一些点
So there are some cases where with the camera moving some points in the image plane will
似乎没动。在那种情况下，我们说运动是不可察觉的。看着这个形象
not appear to move. In that case we say the motion is imperceptible. Looking at the image
我们无法判断相机是否在移动。
we are not able to tell whether the camera is moving or not.
另一个重要的问题是我们所谓的歧义，有时是完全不同的相机
Another important issue is what we call ambiguity and that is at sometimes quite different camera
速度会导致图像发生相同的变化。我们将举一些具体的例子
velocities cause the same change in the image. And we will give some concrete examples of
这两种影响很快就会出现。考虑相机正向移动的情况
both of these effects shortly. Consider the case where the camera is moving in the positive
Z方向我们先前介绍了这种光流辐射模式。
Z direction we have this radiating pattern of optical flow that we introduced earlier.
让我们考虑在图像平面的中间有一个图像平面点。我们
Let's consider we have an image plane point right in the middle of the image plane. We
可以看出，当我们离开中心时，光流向量会变大。在
can see that the optical flow vectors get larger as we move away from the centre. In
事实上在正中心没有明显的速度。但是，如果我直接前往
fact at the very centre there is no apparent velocity. But, if I am heading directly towards
一个物体，它似乎没有向侧面或向上或向下移动;它停留了
an object it doesn't appear to be moving to the side or upwards or downwards; it's stays
到底在哪里。
exactly where it is.
如果我继续沿正Z方向移动，这就是我要击中的东西。
This is the thing that I am going to hit if I keep moving in the positive Z direction.
所以如果我只看一下图像平面中间的一个点;这是不可能的
So if I just look at a point in the middle of the image plane; it's not possible for
我要确定我是否正在前进。
me to determine whether I am moving forwards or not.
不可察觉的运动的另一个例子是相机旋转的情况
Another example of imperceptible motion is the case where the camera is rotating around
它的光轴。因此，如果我考虑图像平面中的一个点，则没有明显的
its optical axis. So again if I consider a point in the image plane there is no apparent
相机旋转时在此特定点的速度。
velocity at this particular point with the camera rotating.
显然，如果我考虑朝向图像边缘的点，则存在显着的速度
Clearly if I consider a point toward the edge of the image there is a significant velocity
由于相机旋转而产生的分量。但是，在图像的中心没有和
component due to the camera rotation. But, in the centre of the image there is none and
我看不出我的相机是否围绕光轴旋转，我无法分辨。
I cannot tell by looking at a point there whether my camera is rotating around the optical axis or not.
让我们计算一下雅可比视觉效果，但这次我们将关注这一点
Let's compute the visual Jacobian but, this time we are going to do it about the point
它位于图像的中心。那是在坐标512,512处，这是主要的点。
which is in the centre of the image. And that is at coordinate 512, 512 that is the principal point.
那是光轴穿透图像平面的地方，我们可以在这里看到它
That's where the optical axis pierces the image plane and we can see that up here in
摄像机对象的参数。
the parameters of the camera object.
我们将在这个特定点计算视觉雅可比，现在让我们来看看
We will compute the visual Jacobian at this particular point, now let's take a look at
当我们移动相机并再次以“X”方向运动时会发生什么。我们
what happens when we move the camera and start again with motion in the "X" direction. We
转置它，我们再次看到这个点在负“U”方向以每秒160像素的速度移动。
transpose that and we see again that this point moves at 160 pixels per second in the negative "U" direction.
现在让我们看看如果我们向“Z”方向移动会发生什么，我们现在看到这个特别的
Now let's see what happens if we move in the "Z" direction and we see now that this particular
点将具有零速度。
point is going to have a zero velocity.
所以我的相机以每秒一米的速度向前移动，直到那一点，
So my camera is moving forward at a meter per second and as far as that particular point,
它的投影图像平面;它根本不动。同样的事情发生在
its projection image plane; it's not moving at all. And the same thing happens in the
围绕光轴旋转的情况。我们再次看到，这一点已经得到了解决
case of rotation around the optical axis. We see again, this particular point has got
图像平面上的零运动。
zero motion on the image plane.
运动模糊是一件有趣的事情。如果我们看光流场是由于
Motion ambiguity is an interesting thing. If we look at the optical flow field due to
在“X”方向上的正速度;我们看到所有的光流向量
positive velocity in the "X' direction; we see that all that all the optical flow vectors
指向左边。
point towards the left.
如果我要围绕“Y”轴以正方向旋转相机，我们就可以获得流量
If I were to rotate the camera in a positive direction around the "Y" axis we get the flow
右侧显示的字段。我们可以看到它们看起来很相似。他们是
field shown here on the right. And we can see that they look quite similar. They are
当然在图像的中间行非常相似，但我们可以看到顶部和
certainly very similar in the middle rows of the image, but we can see at the top and
在图像的底部，对于相机旋转情况，出现光流向量
the bottom of the image that for the camera rotation case the optical flow vectors appear
为了略微弯曲，它们并非全部平行，因为它们是在“X”方向上的纯速度的情况。
to be slightly curved, they are not all parallel as they are in the case of pure velocity in the "X" direction.
翻译和轮换之间存在某种模糊性。如果我翻译相机或
There is some sort of ambiguity between translation and rotation. If I translate the camera or
我旋转相机，我们得到一些类似的光流场。让我们来探讨一下
I rotate the camera we get somewhat similar optical flow fields. Let's explore this in
一点点细节。
a little bit more detail.
在左侧，我们看到由于纯粹的相机转换导致的光流。在右边
On the left we see the optical flow due to pure camera translation. On the right hand
我们有相机围绕“Y”轴旋转的情况。上图显示了
side we have the case for the camera rotating around the "Y" axis. The top graph shows the
相机配有焦距较大的镜头时的情况。这对应于长焦
case when the camera has a lens with a large focal length. This corresponds to a telephoto
或变焦镜头。在这种情况下，我们看到光流模式非常非常相似
or a zoom lens. And we see in this case that the optical flow patterns are very, very similar
确实。但是，如果我们使用的焦距小的镜头对应于宽视场
indeed. However, if we use a lens with a small focal length that corresponds to a wide field
我们看到光流模式现在与模式非常非常不同
of view we see that the optical flow pattern now is very, very different to the pattern
由于纯粹的“X”翻译。这种模糊性实际上取决于焦距
due to pure "X" translation. This ambiguity in fact depends on the focal length of the
镜片。我们可以通过查看雅可比矩阵图像结构的一些细节来解释这一点。
lens. We can explain this by looking in some detail at the structure of the image Jacobian matrix.
考虑相机在“X”方向上具有平移速度的情况。然后那个速度
Consider the case where the camera has translation velocity in the "X" direction. Then that velocity
乘以雅可比图像的这一列。旋转周围会发生模棱两可的情况
multiplies this column of the image Jacobian. The ambiguous case occurs with rotation around
“Y”轴和欧米茄“Y”乘以雅各比矩阵的这一列。
the "Y" axis and omega "Y" multiplies this column of Jacobian matrix.
对于“F”非常大，焦距长的情况;那么这两个词就变成了
For the case where "F" is very large, a long the focal length; then these two terms become
非常相似。那么在这种情况下会发生什么，因为“F”非常大，它在“U”中占主导地位
quite similar. So what happens in this case because "F" is very large it dominates "U'
平方。所以结果实际上是一个常数。它不再是“U”的功能，而是相同的
squared. So the result is effectively a constant. It's no longer a function of "U" and the same
对于第一列，相应的术语不是“U”的函数。所以这两个
for the first column the corresponding term it is not a function of "U". So these two
术语成为类似的功能。
terms become similar functions.
如果我们看第二行，我们可以看到它有“F”，变得非常大，它就在
If we look at the second row we can see that it has "F", becomes very large and it is in
分母。该术语将接近零，并再次变得非常相似
the denominator. This term will approach zero and again becomes very similar to the corresponding
图像雅可比矩阵的第一列中的元素。
elements in the first column of the image Jacobian matrix.
我们可以采用直观的方法解决这个问题。在这里，我们有一个非常广泛的领域
We can take an intuitive approach to this problem. Here we have a very wide field of
查看通过一个非常小的焦距镜头对应的大教堂的图像。和
view image of a cathedral that corresponds through a very small focal length lens. And
在这里，我们看到同一个大教堂的狭窄视野图像，并且对应于一个大的
here we see a narrow field of view image of same cathedral and that corresponds to a large
焦距镜头;如果您愿意，可以使用大变焦镜头，长焦镜头。
focal length lens; a big zoom lens, a telephoto lens if you'd like.
现在，大焦距镜头对应于这个广阔领域的中心部分
Now that large focal length lens corresponds to the central part of this wide field of
看图。所以在宽视野图像的这个中心部分，其中“U”和
view image. So in this central part of the wide field of view image where the "U" and
“V”坐标很小，我们得到这种运动模糊。我们无法判断相机是否合适
"V" coordinates are small we get this motion ambiguity. We can't tell whether the camera
正在旋转或翻译。但是，即使在U和V很大的图像周边，
is rotating or translating. But, even in the periphery of the image where U and V are large,
动议一点也不含糊。相机旋转和相机转换非常原因，
the motion is not ambiguous at all. Camera rotation and camera translation cause very,
光流现象非常不同。这种模糊性肯定与焦距有关。
very different optical flow phenomenon. This ambiguity is very definitely related to the focal length.
显然，旋转运动和平移运动是非常非常不同的。但是，什么
Clearly rotational motion and translational motion are very, very different. But, what
我们刚才说的是使用图像传感器;就像我们的眼睛一样，这是不可能的
we've just been saying is that using an image sensor; just like our eye that it is not possible
让我们一般地说出一些旋转运动和一些平移运动之间的区别。
for us to tell in general the difference between some rotational motions and some translational motions.
当然，这将成为使用视觉来控制机器人的一个障碍。而且有点儿
Surely this would be a showstopper for using vision to control robots. And it is a bit
问题和解决问题的一种方法是使用单独的传感器来测量旋转。
of a problem and one way to get around that is to use a separate sensor to measure rotation.
这是一张旋转测量单元的图片，里面有陀螺仪传感器
So this is a picture of a rotational measurement unit which has got gyroscope sensors in it
它可以独立测量机器人的旋转，我们可以使用这些额外的信息
which can measure independently the rotation of a robot and we can use this extra information
消除我们从视觉传感器获得的信息的歧义。
to disambiguate the information that we get from our visual sensor.
但是，我们呢？我们有眼睛，清楚地告诉我们，我们可以很容易地确定我们是否在旋转
But, what about us? We have our eyes and clearly for us we can easily determine if we are rotating
或者我们是否正在翻译。是的，我们可以，但为此，我们也使用惯性传感器。
or whether we are translating. Yes we can, but to do that we also use inertial sensors.
我们实际上有旋转传感器。在我们的内耳中有这三个
We actually have rotational sensors in our head. In our inner ear there are these three
半圆形运河，它们测量我们头部的角速度，我们有三个
semi-circular canals and they measure the angular velocity of our head and we have three
我们左耳的传感器和右耳的三个传感器。而我们的大脑融合了
sensors in our left ear and three sensors in our right ear. And our brain fuses the
来自我们内耳的旋转信息和我们的光流信息
rotational information that comes from our inner ear with our optical flow information
来自我们的眼睛。
that comes from our eyes.
它融合在我们的大脑中，它为我们提供了一个关于我们运动的非常明确的信息
It is fused in our brain it gives us a very unambiguous information about our motion whether
我们正在轮换或是否正在翻译。
we're rotating or whether we are translating.
这是一种非常强大的错觉。
This is a very very powerful illusion.
我在旋转的鼓里面，我的眼睛可以检测到这个鼓的运动。
I am inside a rotating drum, and my eye can detect the motion of this drum.
我的眼睛和大脑正在计算我们所谓的光流和光流
My eye and my brain are computing what we call optical flow, and this optical flow
由旋转鼓引起的是与我以这种方式旋转头部时相同的光学流动，
that’s caused by that rotating drum is the same sort of optical flow that I get if I rotate my head this way,
或者我这样转动我的头。
or I rotate my head that way.
而这种特殊的幻觉让我感到有点不安，
And this particular illusion causes me to feel a little bit uneasy,
因为我用眼睛得到的信息-光流-
because the information that I get with my eyes — the optical flow —
告诉我，我的头在左右移动，
tells me that my head is moving from side to side,
但我耳朵里的陀螺仪传感器告诉我，这种情况并没有发生。
but the gyroscopic sensors in my ears tell me that’s not happening.
因此，我的耳朵告诉我的态度之间存在脱节，
So there’s a disconnect between what my ears are telling me about my attitude,
我的眼睛告诉我的动作是什么，
and what my eyes are telling me about my motion,
这会导致晕船或轻微恶心的感觉，
and that leads to the sensation of seasickness or a slight nausea,
这就是我坚持这些铁轨的原因。
which is why I’m holding on very tightly to these rails.